In this video, I'm going to show you how
to make custom
multi-cell fixture profiles.
Hey everyone, today I'm launching a new
series all about making
custom profiles in Blackout.
If you've been using Blackout for any
amount of time, you know
that part of what makes Blackout
special as a lighting console is our
fixture database. We
have one of the best fixture
databases in the industry, and that's
because our profiles are
human-made and human-verified.
As you can see in our fixture database,
we have these green tags
next to all the profiles that
have been human-verified to work. And we
go a step further and use
these blue "prefer" tags
to tell you that these are profiles that
we recommend using for your sets.
Now this video is about making a custom
profile for yourself, but
I'm bringing up our fixture
database because one of the best things
you can do to set yourself
up for success if you have a
light that we don't have a profile for is
let us know. Use the help center and
request a new fixture
and we will have it in there very
quickly. But without further
ado, let's get into making our
own custom multi-cell fixture profile. As
a quick refresher, a
multi-cell profile is a profile that
contains multiple cells which are
essentially separate units within the
same profile that you
can control individually. Commonly, this
is used for pixels in a
unit like an aesterotitan tube.
But the first example we'll look at is a
super basic six-channel
dimmer that you want to be
tied into all one fixture. The example
that I think makes the
most sense is six space lights
overhead into a six-channel dimmer. So
basically we have six lights
overhead that we're probably
controlling altogether most of the time,
but there might be moments
where we want to dim them
individually. So making a profile for
this makes a lot of sense. So
let's take a look. We'll start
off by navigating to the patch tab and
going to add fixtures. And
here we'll now create new.
We can call this "6-by dimmer" and for
the mode we'll put 8-bit
because there are 8-bit dimmers
and 6-channel. And this
will be "8-bit 6-cell dimmer".
And we'll change the DMX footprint to be
6 and save. Now we're in
the fixture editor and the
first thing I'm going to do is actually
close out of here because
what I need to do is actually
change all of my modules to cells. Okay,
before we go any further, let's think
about this for a second.
We have a dimmer box with six channels
and each of those channels gets an
address. There's no master
channel that controls all of them, so we
need to tell blackout to
create that for us. Because when
you enter the address, that's just
controlling the first channel on the
dimmer. So let's say you put
an address 1, then address 1 is
controlling dimmer 1, address 2 is
controlling dimmer 2,
address 3 is controlling dimmer 3, and so
on and so forth, all the
way to 6. There's no address
anywhere in there that controls all of
them. So when you're
building a profile, you only define
actual parameters that your fixture has.
So I know that's a bit
confusing, so let me show you what I
mean. Here we have a head cell, but
blackout is going to
automatically create the head for us.
So we're going to tap the pencil here and
change this to a cell and
we'll relabel it "cell". Now we
can add our parameter, which is just
intensity. I'm hitting new channel right
here and I'm searching
for intensity. I can use this filter,
scroll down until I see
intensity and all the defaults here
are fine. Beautiful. Now we just have to
create five more modules.
I'll hit new module, I'll come
up to this list and select our cell and
then make sure I switch it to cell and
hit save. And I'll do
the same thing until I have six. Cell,
switch it to cell, save.
Okay, so now I have six cells that
all have their own intensity parameter.
All I have to do now is hit save and
patch it in. So I'll
hit save, hit patch. We'll keep the
defaults for now just to test it. Now if
I go to my fixture tab,
there we go. In the head, if I bring up
the intensity, it brings up all of them,
but I can clear out and then select just
one of them and bring that up and down.
Then I can grab the head and make all of
them full. I can grab the
head and go offset cells only
even and just turn the evens off. So
let's do one more together.
That's a very common fixture.
RGB pixel tape. The problem with RGB
pixel tape is each pixel
just has three parameters,
red, green, blue, there's no dimmer. So
it's similar. We have to
tell blackout to create a
dimmer to dim each channel using those
red, green, blue channels and create a
master dimmer for the
whole thing. So let's take a look at
that. Let's say we're doing three pixel
tape. We'll go to add
fixtures and create new and we'll call
this three pixel RGB
tape. We'll say RGB a bit.
You can look at some of our other
profiles to see what our naming
conventions are. And so I have
red, green, blue over three pixels. So
that will be a nine channel
footprint. We'll save that.
And I'll do the same thing by starting
off and turning this
into a cell. Because again,
address one on this pixel tape is red of
the first cell of the first
pixel address two is green of
the first cell. And then address three is
blue of the first cell.
And then address four is red
of the second cell and there are no
dimmers. So blackout will
just create those for us.
So we'll switch this to cell and I'll
call it pixel and save.
And save. And I'll do new channel select
parameter and I'll type in red.
Find red, save all the defaults for red
are perfect. So let's
save that new channel.
We'll search for blue. New
channel. I'll search for green.
And save. And this is our first pixel
done. So now we'll do
the same thing new module.
And I'll select the pixel. Make sure it's
a cell and save. And you can
see that starting at address
four. And then I'll do it one more time.
Select a module pixel,
change it to a cell and save.
So now let's patch this profile in and
take a look. I'll save it.
I'll patch it.
Just for visibility, I'll change the
color here to a red. So
now I can grab my fixture
and start dimming it up. And you can see
blackout built us a virtual dimmer.
And if I go into table view, I can see
what blackout's actually doing.
Blackout has just turned the red channel
on. If I saturated down,
we get all the channels at full because
that's white. And as I dim it down,
it dims the virtual dimmer. But if I
switch to my output value view state, I
can see that as I dim
down, this is what blackout is actually
doing. It's dimming down
the color channels. So that's
what a virtual dimmer does. So here I
have some pixel tape
connected to a DMX decoder. And if I
bring my virtual dimmer up, you can see
this whole section glows,
these are my three pixels.
And I can come in here and turn my two
end pixels off and just
get these on this tape.
One pixel is three diodes, and then I can
turn the second one on.
And then I can come in here,
saturate them up, move them around the
color wheel. And you can see it works
perfectly. So now I can
just tap the fixture, grab the whole
thing. Look at that, put them at full,
make them all the same
color. And there you go. That's how to
make a custom profile for
multi-cell units. Next in this
series, I'll be taking a look at moving
lights and more complex
fixtures. But let me know in the
comments what you want to see more of.
And of course, if you have
a fixture that you're unsure
about, let us know in the help center and
we'll get it in there for you. Okay,
that's it. See you next time.